Finding Aid for Arthur Lyon Cross Papers 1897-1940
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Arthur Lyon Cross Papers 1897-1940
Cross, Arthur Lyon, 1873-1940.
Professor of English history at University of Michigan. Correspondence with European and American historians, publishing houses, editors of learned journals, members of his family, and friends; also manuscripts of books and articles, lecture notes, student records, business papers, personal account books, diaries, 1938-1940, with comments on world events, and miscellaneous papers; and photographs.
851024 Aa 2; Ac
16 linear feet
1 oversize folders
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Arthur Lyon Cross and his estate (donor no. 1203 ). The great bulk of the collection came to the library in 1940.
The collection is open for research.
Arthur Lyon Cross was born November 14, 1873 in Portland, Maine. He graduated from Harvard College with an AB degree in 1895. While at Harvard, Cross worked with Edward Channing, continuing his studies, receiving his A.M. in 1896 and his Ph.D. in 1899. His thesis was later published as The Anglican Episcopate and the American Colonies.
Cross came to the University of Michigan in 1899 as an instructor. He was promoted to professor in 1911 and in 1916 he was appointed Richard Hudson Professor of English History. Cross was noted for his courses on English and constitutional history, and for his various writings, especially A history of England and Greater Britain and his history of St. Andrew's Church in Ann Arbor. Cross died June 21, 1940.
The Cross papers are divided into the following series: Correspondence; Miscellaneous and undated papers; Personal/Biographical; University of Michigan; Publications, articles, and related; Research and lecture materials, and Photographs.
Subjects:
Arab Students Union (University of Michigan); Barrett, Albert M. (Albert Moore), 1871-1936.; Cross, Arthur Lyon, 1873-1940.; Delta Upsilon Fraternity. University of Michigan Chapter.; Donaldson, Bruce McNaughton, 1891-1940.; Faculty Club (University of Michigan); Historians--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Katholepistemiad Club (University of Michigan); Lawyers' Club (University of Michigan); Lee, Alfred Oughton, 1873-1938.; Michigan Historical Collections.; Michigan Schoolmasters' Club.; Phi Beta Kappa. Alpha Chapter (University of Michigan); Prismatic Club (Detroit, Mich.); Rhodes Scholars.; Sill, John Mahelm Berry, 1831-1901.; St. Andrew's Episcopal Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.); University of Michigan. Dept. of History.; University of Michigan--Examinations.; University of Michigan--History.; University of Michigan. Research Club.; University of Michigan. Senate.; University of Michigan. Student Religious Association.; Ziwet, Alexander, 1853-1928.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Apostles Club (University of Michigan); Canoes.; Clothing and dress.; Costumes.; Cross, Arthur Lyon, 1873-1940.; Cross family.; Dwellings.; Families.; Interiors.; Leland (Mich.); Passengers.; Picnics.; Private libraries.; Tahiti.; University of Michigan--Faculty.
Contributors:
Abbot, Waldo, 1888-; Adams, Randolph Greenfield, 1892-1951.; Aiton, Arthur Scott, 1894-1955.; Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916.; Angell, Robert Cooley, 1899-1984; Barbour, Levi L. (Levi Lewis), 1840-1925.; Bates, Henry Moore, 1869-1949.; Beal, Junius E. (Junius Emery), 1860-1942.; Bigelow, Samuel Lawrence, 1870-1947.; Boak, Arthur Edward Romilly, 1888-1962.; Bonner, Campbell, b. 1876.; Bromage, Arthur W. (Arthur Watson), 1904-1979.; Buck, Solon Justus, 1884-1962.; Burton, Marion Le Roy, 1874-1925.; Cabot, Hugh, 1872-1945.; Channing, Edward, 1856-1931.; Chapin, Roy D. (Roy Dikeman), 1880-1936.; Clements, William L. (William Lawrence), 1861-1934.; Cocker, Benjamin Clark.; Coffey, Hobart R., 1896-1969.; Coller, Frederick A.; Cooley, Mortimer E. (Mortimer Elwyn), 1855-1944.; Coulter, Glenn Monroe, 1894-; Couzens, James, 1872-1936.; Crane, Verner W., 1889-1974; Curtis, Heber Doust, 1872-1942.; Curtiss, Ralph Hamilton, 1880-1929.; Cushny, Arthur R. (Arthur Robertson), 1866-1926.; Dean, Henry Stewart, 1830-1915.; Denison, Charles Simeon, 1849-1913.; Dow, Earle Wilbur, 1868-1946.; Dumond, Dwight Lowell, 1895-1976; Eaton, John Wallace, 1886-1948.; Effinger, John Robert, 1869-1933.; Fairlie, John A. (John Archibald), 1872-1947.; Farrand, Max, 1869-1945.; Ford, Guy Stanton, 1873-1962.; Franklin, Kenneth J.; Frayer, William Alley.; Fuller, George N. (George Newman), 1873-1957.; Furstenberg, Albert Carl, 1890-1969.; Gale, Esson M. (Esson McDowell), 1884-1964; Glaser, Otto Charles, 1880-; Goddard, Edwin C. (Edwin Charles), 1865-1942.; Gomberg, Moses, 1866-1947.; Hamilton, George L. (George Livingstone), 1874-1940.; Harris, Thomas L. (Thomas Le Grand), 1863-1941.; Hart, Albert Bushnell, 1854-1943.; Hinsdale, Mary L.; Hinsdale, Mildred, 1871-1971.; Hobbs, William Herbert, 1864-1952.; Hubbard, Lucius L. (Lucius Lee), 1849-1933.; Hudson, Richard, 1845-1915.; Hutchins, Harry B. (Harry Burns), 1847-1930.; Hyma, Albert, 1893-1978; Jordan, Myra Beach, 1863-1946.; Kelsey, Francis W. (Francis Willey), b. 1858.; Khalaf, Johan I.; Kirchner, Otto, 1846-1920.; Koch, Theodore Wesley, 1871-1941.; Lincoln, Joseph Newhall, 1892-1945.; Little, Clarence C. (Clarence Cook), b. 1888.; Lloyd, Alfred H. (Alfred Henry), 1864-1927.; Lombard, Warren P. (Warren Plimpton), 1855-1939.; McCormick, John Newton, 1863-1939.; McLaughlin, Andrew Cunningham, 1861-1947.; McLaughlin, Lois T. (Lois Thompson); Michener, Earl C. (Earl Cory), 1876-1957.; Moore, Charles, 1855-1942.; Murfin, James Orin, 1875-1940.; Newkirk, Henry Wirt, 1854-1946.; Novy, Frederick George, 1864-1957.; Osborn, Chase S. (Chase Salmon), b. 1860.; Patterson, George W. (George Washington), 1864-1930.; Patterson, Merib Rowley.; Paxson, Frederic L. (Frederic Logan), 1877-1948.; Peirsol, Thomas Reardon.; Pillsbury, W. B. (Walter Bowers), 1872-1960.; Price, Hereward Thimbleby, 1880-1964.; Quaife, Milo Milton, 1880-1959.; Reed, John Oren, 1856-1916.; Reeves, Jesse Siddall, 1872-1942; Ruthven, Alexander Grant, 1882-1971.; Sadler, Herbert Charles, 1872-; Sawyer, Walter H. (Walter Hulme), 1861-1931.; Scott, S. Morley.; Shaw, Wilfred Byron, 1881-1959.; Sink, Charles A. (Charles Albert), 1879-1972.; Slosson, Preston W. (Preston William), 1892-1984; Smith, Shirley Wheeler, 1875-1959.; Spaulding, Thomas M. (Thomas Marshall), b. 1882.; Stanley, Albert A. (Albert Augustus), 1851-1932.; Strohm, Adam Julius, 1870-; Tapping, Theodore Hawley, 1889-1969.; Tatlock, Henry, 1848-1942.; Tatlock, John S. P. (John Strong Perry), 1876-1948.; Turner, Edward Raymond, 1881-1929.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.; Van Tyne, Claude Halstead, 1869-1930.; Warthin, Aldred Scott, 1866-1931.; Wenley, R. M. (Robert Mark), 1861-1929.; White, Andrew Dickson, 1832-1918.; White, Lee A., b. 1886.; Winship, George Parker, 1871-1952.; Woolley, Joseph William.; Yost, Fielding Harris, 1871-1946.
Genre/Form:
Account books.; Albums.; Cliches-verre.; Diaries.; Photographs.
- Correspondence
  - 1897-1911, 86 folders (Box 1)
  - 1912-1922, 83 folders (Box 2)
  - 1923-1930, 75 folders (Box 3)
  - 1931-1936, 66 folders (Box 4)
  - 1937-May 1940, 40 folders (Box 5)
- Miscellaneous and undated papers
  - Professional and personal, 26 folders (Box 5)
- Personal/Biographical
  - Diaries, notebooks, account books (Box 15)
  - Biographical and autobiographical material (Box 6)
    (see also citations in oversize folder Ac)
  - Membership cards (Box 6)
  - Prismatic Club of Detroit 1917-1939 (Box 6)
  - Delta Upsilon Fraternity 1907-1939 (Box 6)
  - St. Andrews Episcopal Church, Ann Arbor 1918-1940 (Box 6)
  - Visas and Passports (Box 6)
- University of Michigan
  - Committee and departmental papers
    - Official appointment notices from the University of Michigan 1902-1938 (Box 6)
    - History Department matters 1916-1940, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Committee on Honorary Degrees 1922-1939 (Box 6)
    - Committee on Honors Convocations 1927-1931 (Box 6)
    - Committee on Scholarly Publications 1916-1940 (Box 6)
    - Rhodes Scholarship Committee 1927-1939 (Box 6)
    - Committee on Combined Curricula 1933-1938 (Box 6)
  - Biographical sketches and memorials of university personages
    - Dr. Albert Moore Barrett 1936 (Box 6)
    - Edward Channing (Reminiscence of) undated (Box 6)
    - William Lawrence Clements 1934 (Box 6)
    - Ralph Hamilton Curtiss 1929 (Box 6)
    - Bruce McNaughton Donaldson 1940 (Box 6)
    - Earl W. Dow (Retirement of) undated (Box 6)
    - Alfred Oughton Lee 1939 (Box 6)
    - George Washington Patterson undated (Box 6)
    - Claude Halstead Van Tyne 1930 (Box 6)
    - Robert Mark Wenley undated (Box 6)
    - Alexander Ziwet 1928 (Box 6)
  - English History Course undated, 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous University affairs, 20 folders (Box 6)
- Publications, articles, and related
  - Papers concerning publication of his books 1905-1921 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence concerning corrections for A History of England, 1915-1921 (Box 6)
  - Book Reviews of A History of England, 1914 (Box 6)
  - Book Reviews of the Anglican Episcopate, 1902-1903 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence for the National Board for Historical Service 1917-1918 (Box 7)
  - Subscriptions to the National Bibliography of Modern British History 1909-1916, 4 folders (Box 7)
  - Manuscript of A History of St. Andrews, Church, Ann Arbor, 5 folders (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous Short Articles and Speeches, 45 folders (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous Short Articles and Speeches, 22 folders (Box 8)
  - Book Reviews, 33 folders (Box 8)
  - Speeches, 12 folders (Box 8)
- Research and lecture materials
  - Notes on Mortmain, 21 folders (Box 9)
  - Bibliography of British law, 16 folders (Box 9)
  - Research notes, 8 folders (Box 9)
  - Harvard student lecture notes 1892-1895 (Box 10)
  - Harvard student lecture notes 1892-1895 (Box 11)
  - Lecture notes on English Constitutional History and general (Box 12)
  - English History (Box 12)
  - Lecture notes on general English History (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous exams for history courses (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous exams for history courses (Box 14)
  - Research notes (Box 14)
- Visual Materials
  - Photographs (Box 16)
    - Portraits and informal snapshots of Cross, family members and friends, 5 folders; 3 volumes (Box 16)
    - Photographs of travel 1920s to Tahiti and elsewhere, 2 folders; 1 volumes (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous snapshots (include Leland, Mich.) (Box 16)
    - Two glass portraits, cliches-verre (Box 16)
      stored with UAx images
  - Print from wood engraving of a Chinese warrior (Folder 1)
    includes explanatory letter 1928
Selective Index to Correspondents
Abbot, Waldo, 1888-
April 2, 1928
Adams, Randolph Greenfield, 1892-1951.
Letters, Oct. 29, Dec. 22., 1925., Jan. 23, Feb. 16, June 13, 1932, March 8, Oct.8, 1934, July 23, 1935, Sept. 23, 1936, Sept. 29, 1937, Nov. 9, 1938, March 23, 1939; also letter Jan. 10, 1939, from Cross to D. R. Stuart, Princeton University, concerning Randolph G. Adams.
Aiton, Arthur Scott, 1894-1955.
Mar. 26, 1936
Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916.
Letters, June 22, 1908; 1902, [n.d. placed at end of year]; Jan. 18, 1909; Jan. 13, 1911; May 1912; March 16, 1913, from James B. Angell; also official appointment notices from President Angell, May 22, 1902; May 16, 1904; June 21, 1907
Angell, Robert Cooley, 1899-
Jan. 23, 1933
Arab Student Union (University of Michigan)
March 3, 1930, of Johan I. Khalaf relating to the re-establishment of the Arab Students Union.
Barbour, Levi L. (Levi Lewis), 1840-1925.
Nov. 29, 1902; April 10, Nov. 30, 1903; March 24, 1904; Feb. 15.July 2, Dec. 19, 1906; Jan. 1, April 6, 1908; July 25, 1916; July 1, 1918
Barrett, Albert Moore, 1871-1936.
Memorial, 1936, to Barrett written by Cross
Bates, Henry Moore, 1869-1949.
April 11, 1928; Aug. 6, 1930; Nov. 22, 1933
Beal, Junius E. (Junius Emery), 1860-1942.
May 21, 1917; Dec. 4, 1928; Jan. 8, 1929; April 28, 1936
Bigelow, Samuel Lawrence, 1870-1947.
March 3, 1913; Sept. 5, 1919; Oct. 20, 1929; Feb. 28, 1940
Boak, Arthur Edward Romilly, 1888-1962.
June 19, 1915, July 26, 1916, Sept. 15, 1916, May 30, 1917, July 12, 1928, Sept. 15, 1931, Nov. 22, 1931, May 1, 1932, Mar. 29, 1939.
Bonner, Campbell, b. 1876.
Aug. 12, 1919
Bromage, Arthur W. (Arthur Watson), 1904-1979.
March 23, 1932
Buck, Solon Justus, 1884-1962.
Mar. 31, 1926, Apr. 14, 1926, Apr. 16, 1926, Aug. 10, 1926, Nov. 24, 1926.
Burton, Marion Le Roy, 1874-1925.
Letters, April 7, Oct. 21, Oct. 22, Dec. 1, 1920; April 12, 1921; Nov. 3, 1923, March 12, 1924 [See also folder of official University correspondence.]
Cabot, Hugh, 1872-1945.
Oct. 18, 1919; Feb. 21, 1930; Dec. 30, 1934; Dec. 26, 1935; Nov. 5, 1936
Channing, Edward, 1856-1931.
1900-1930; also memorial sketch of Channing by Cross
Chapin, Roy D. (Roy Dikeman), 1880-1936.
Sept. 8, 1929
Clements, William L. (William Lawrence), 1861-1934
Feb. 2, 1917; Nov. 30, 1920; Feb. 4, Dec. 20, Dec. 28, 1921; Feb. 3, July 13, 1922; Oct. 21, Dec. 5, Dec. 7, 1925; Jan. 11, Feb. 16, April 28, 1926; June 19, 1928, Dec. 12, 1929; March 24, 1931, May 15, 1933; also biographical sketch of Clements
Cocker, Benjamin Clark.
Dec. 24, 1919
Coffey, Hobart R., 1896-1969.
Dec. 5, 1928
Coller, Frederick A.
Oct. 25, 1934
Cooley, Mortimer E. (Mortimer Elwyn), 1855-1944.
Nov. 19, Dec. 14, 1932; April 10, 1934; April 19, 1935; March 30, 1938
Coulter, Glenn Monroe, 1894-
Jan. 26, 1918
Couzens, James, 1872-1936.
Dec. 15, 1930
Crane, Verner Winslow, 1889-
June 9, 1938, postcard, April 17, 1938
Curtis, Heber Doust, 1872-1942.
Nov. 1, 1934 and Nov. 29 1939
Curtiss, Ralph Hamilton, 1880-1929.
July 30, 1918; Sept.18, 1919; postcard, March 21, 1926; also memorial to Curtiss, 1929, by Cross.
Cushny, Arthur R. (Arthur Robertson), 1866-1926.
Aug. 8, 1908; and letter, March 19, 1926, from R. M. Wenley describing the death of Cushny.
Dean, Henry Stewart, 1830-1915.
Nov. 3, 1902
Denison, Charles Simeon, 1849-1913.
Feb. 28, 1902 and Nov. 19, 1903
Donaldson, Bruce McNaughton, 1891-1940.
Biographical sketch of Donaldson on occasion of his death.
Dow, Earle Wilbur, 1868-1946.
July 4, Sept. 15, 1901; June 20, July 6, 1902; Jan. 8, 1927; June 14, 1938; also memorial on the retirement of Dow, 1938
Dumond, Dwight Lowell, 1895-
Feb. 18, 1939
Eaton, John Wallace, 1886-1948.
June 14 ?, July 31, Oct, 18, postcard, Oct. 18, postcard, Nov. 15, Dec. 30, 1935; Feb. 2, April 28, 1936
Effinger, John Robert, 1869-1933.
Feb. 17, 1903; Jan. 9, 1908; postcard, June 28, 1911; June 19, 1917; Oct. 29, 1930
Faculty Club (University of Michigan)
Mimeographed letter, Nov. 24, 1911, relative to the establishment of the faculty club
Fairlie, John A. (John Archibald), 1872-1947.
Feb. 27, March 22, 1908
Farrand, Max, 1869-1945.
April 11, 1931; Feb. 12, 1937
Ford, Guy Stanton, 1873-1962.
Feb. 20, 1912; Jan. 9, 1917; Jan. 16, 1940
Franklin, Kenneth J
April 2, 1926
Frayer, William Alley
Feb. 17, 1930
Fuller, George N. (George Newman), 1873-1957.
Dec. 9, 1906; July 23, 1907; Oct. 12, 1922; Oct. 5, 1939
Furstenberg, Albert Carl, 1890-1969.
Feb. 6, 1940
Gale, Esson McDowell, 1884-
Jan. 25, and Jan. 30, 1939
Glaser, Otto Charles, 1880-
Feb. 11, 1910; Jan. 7, 1921; Feb. 11, 1923
Goddard, Edwin C. (Edwin Charles), 1865-1942.
Nov. 15, 1907 and Nov. 15, 1933
Gomberg, Moses, 1866-1947.
March 23, 1936
Hamilton, George L. (George Livingstone), 1874-1940.
April 30, 1910
Harris, Thomas L. (Thomas Le Grand), 1863-1941.
May 12, 1930
Hart.Albert Bushnell, 1854-1943.
July 14, 1897-Nov. 18, 1924
Hinsdale, Mary L.
Oct. 18, 1919 and June 9, 1937
Hinsdale, Mildred, 1871-1971.
Oct. 27, 1918
Hobbs, William Herbert, 1864-1952.
Dec. 16, 1919
Hubbard, Lucius L. (Lucius Lee), 1849-1933.
March 14, 1933
Hudson, Richard, 1845-1915.
Aug. 25, 1902; Aug, 3, 1907; March 16, June 5, June 10, 1910
Hutchins, Harry B. (Harry Burns), 1847-1930.
June 5, 1916; March 8, 1917; April 11, 1928
Hyma, Albert, 1893-
June 25, 1920
Jordan, Myra Beach, 1863-1946.
July 7, 1902, from Merib R. Patterson mentioning her appointment as Dean
Kelsey, Francis W. (Francis Willey), b. 1858.
Dec. 19, 1908
Khalaf, Johan I.
March 30, 1930, relative to the re-establishment of the Arab Students Union.
Kirchner, Otto, 1846-1920.
June 3, 1917
Koch, Theodore Wesley, 1871-1941.
July 30, Aug. 5, 1919, and July 9, 1921
Lawyers Club (University of Michigan
Feb. 2, 1928, from Gerald E. White of the Lawyers Club concerning the adoption of a lawyers club emblem.
Lee, Alfred Oughton, 1873-1938.
Mmorial, 1939, to Alfred O.Lee by Cross.
Lincoln, Joseph Newhall, 1892-1945.
Nov. 5, 1919
Little, Clarence C. (Clarence Cook), b. 1888.
July 22, Oct. 26, 1925; March 1, 1927
'
Lloyd, Alfred Henry, 1864-1927.
Feb. 10, 1910, Sept, 6, 1919, Dec. 19, 1923, and April 22, 1927
Lombard, Warren P. (Warren Plimpton), 1855-1939.
Nov. 10, 1906; March 13, 1923; May 18, 1927
McCormick, John Newton, 1863-1939.
Jan. 3, Dec. 14, 1916; postcard, April 24, 1917; May 10, Sept. 21, 1925
McLaughlin, Andrew Cunningham, 1861-1947.
June 23, 1902; Oct. 5, 1903; Feb. 20, March 3, April 11, 12, May 13, 19, 1904; Feb. 13, Oct. 15, 1907; Feb. 23, 1908; Feb. 13, 1912; Feb. 16, Dec. 7, Dec. 11, Dec. 17, 1915; Jan. 11, 1916; March 12, 1918; Nov. 12, 1924; March 24, 1932
McLaughlin, Lois T. (Lois Thompson).
Feb. 7, 15, 1904, Feb. 19, 1907; Feb. 16, 1908, Feb. 14, 1909; Feb.16, 1911; Feb. 17, 1912
Michener, Earl C. (Earl Cory), 1876-1957.
Dec. 22, 1930, letter, Feb. 22, 1937, from Michener to J. S. Reeves.
Michigan Historical Collections.
Oct. 21, 1932 (Alexander G. Ruthven to A. L. Cross, concerning the desirability of appointing a curator of University history.
Michigan Schoolmaster's Club.
Correspondence, 1932-1935, concerning the Michigan Schoolmaster's Club.
Moore, Charles, 1855-1942.
Feb. 21, 1923; letters, Dec, 11 and 19, 1929, of J. T. Jameson to Cross concerning Moore's life membership in the American Historical Association; letter, Dec. 27, 1929, of Jameson to Gross quoting letter, Dec. 23, 1929, of Moore.
Murfin, James Orin, 1875-1940.
Nov. 4, 1920; Jan. 28, Feb. 5, 1936; Feb. 10, 1936; Oct, 5, 1938
Newkirk, Henry Wirt, 1854-1946.
May 21, 1931, and Feb. 2, 1932
Novy, Frederick George, 1864-1957.
Oct. 9, 1938
Osborn, Chase S. (Chase Salmon), b. 1860.
Feb. 7, 1910
Paxson, Frederic Logan, 1877-1948.
April 2, June 8, Oct-13, 1910; Feb. 26, June 14, Oct. 31, 1911; Feb. 27, March 28, 1912; Jan. 10, Nov. 28, Dec. 17, 1915; April 15, 1916; Feb. 22, 1918; Dec. 7, 1919; April 9, 1922; Jan. 31, [1930]
Peirsol, Thomas Reardon.
May 18, Nov. 4, 1936; Aug .26, Oct. 19, 1937
Phi Beta Kappa. Alpha Chapter, University of Michigan.
Correspondence of Cross with Alpha Chapter of Phi Beta Kappa, 1923-1938
Pillsbury, W. B. (Walter Bowers), 1872-1960.
March 13, 1923
Price, Hereward Thimbleby, 1880-1964.
Sept. 28, 1937
Prismatic Club (Detroit, Mich.)
Correspondence, announcements of meetings, lists of speakers, 1917-1940.
Quaife, Milo Milton, 1880-1959.
Jan. 9 and Jan. 29, 1907
Reed, John Oren, 1856-1916.
March 15 and May 6, 1910
Reeves, Jesse Siddall, 1872-
Nov. 27, 1931
Rhodes Scholars.
Correspondence, reports of the committee and information on candidates for Rhodes Scholarships, 1927-1939.
Ruthven, Alexander Grant, 1882-
Feb. 28, 1917; Sept. 23, 1930; Jan. 19, 1936; Feb. 21, 1938; May 10, 1939; also letter, Oct. 21, 1932, from Ruthven, concerning the desirability of appoint ing a curator of University history.
Sadler, Herbert Charles, 1872-
July 16, Aug. 29, 1907; Feb. 19, March 13, 1910; June 27, postcard, July 15, 1911; May 19, postcard, May 20, June 23, July 27, Aug. 11, Nov. 12, Dec. 29, postcard, Dec. 29, 1918; Aug. 3, 1919; July 25, 1936
St. Andrews Episcopal Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.)
Form letters and correspondence, 1918-1940, relating to St. Andrews Episcopal Church.
Sawyer, Walter H. (Walter Hulme), 1861-1931.
Nov. 14, 1929
Scott, S. Morley.
Jan. 21, 22, 1926; May 25, 1938
Shaw, Wilfred Byron, 1881-1959.
Dec. 28, 1937
Sill, John Mahelm Berry, 1831-1901.
Feb.7, 1921 from Marion B. Rosenberry containing reference to John M. B. Sill as a contributor to the first St. Andrews Church, Ann Arbor.
Sink, Charles Albert, 1879-1972.
Sept. 30, 1932
Slosson, Preston W. (Preston William), 1892-
Feb. 8, 1933
Smith, Shirley Wheeler, 1875-1959.
Feb. 16, 1939
Spaulding, Thomas M. (Thomas Marshall), b. 1882.
July 31, Aug. 21, 1928; postcard, Sept. 26 [1929]
Stanley, Albert A. (Albert Augustus), 1851-1932.
July 30, 1911
Strohm, Adam Julius, 1870-
Feb. 23, 1926
Tapping, Theodore Hawley, 1889-1969.
Feb. 28, 1927; May 2, 1929; Jan. 16, 1930 [carbon]; letter to Edward D. Smith concerning the establishment by the Univ. of Mich. Alumni Club of Columbus, of a fellowship in the history department; also letters, Dec. 19, 1930; Dec. 23, 1931; June 18, 1935
Tatlock, Henry, 1848-1942.
April 22, 1902; April 26, 1915; March 17, 1917; Nov. 24, 1937; also letters, Nov. 4, 1936, and Aug. 26, 1937, from T. Reardon Peirsol to Cross concerning the presentation of portrait to Tatlock
Tatlock, John S. P. (John Strong Perry), 1876-1948.
March 26, 1910; March 31, July 21, 1911; July 6, 1916; [April 25, 1917]; Jan. 8, 1920; postcard, Nov. 22, 1923; May 25, 1931; Sept. 25, Dec. 7, Dec. 30, 1936; note, Sept. 15, 1937
Turner, Edward Raymond, 1881-1929.
April 28, July 31, 1911; Nov. 12, 1921; June 20, 1922; May 10, 1928; Dec. 4, 1929
University of Michigan--History
Manuscript, The University of Michigan In Ann Arbor, 1837-1937, by A.L.Cross.
University of Michigan. Research Club.
Eligibility rules for membership in the Research Club; membership list, Jan. 1, 1923; and correspondence, 1932-1939.
University of Michigan. Senate.
Reports and correspondence relating to various senate committees, 1926-1934; minutes of meetings of the Senate Council, April [1935], Feb. 1937; reports of various committees to the council.
University of Michigan. Student Religious Association.
Oct. 7, 1927, from Student Christian Association, [Wm. D. Brumbaugh, Jr.] concerning revision of charter and proposed new program; letter, April 9, 1928.
Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.
Jan. 5, 1931
Van Tyne, Claude Halstead, 1869-1930.
March 17, 1910, re: the establishnent of the group system of electives at Michigan; Sept. 4, 1910; April 30, 1918; May 8, 1918; Dec.28, [1921]; Aug. 29, 1923; also memorial to Van Tyne by Cross, 1930.
Warthin, Aldred Scott, 1866-1931.
Sept. 14, 1908
Wenley, R. M. (Robert Mark), 1861-1929.
June 16, 1916; postcard; Dec. 8, 1918; Dec. 13, 1921; March 19, 1926, describing the death of Arthur R. Cushny; May 19, 1926, to H.B.Hutchins; June 18, 1926; June 1, 1928; from Robert M. Wenley; also biographical sketch of Wenley on occasion of his death
White, Andrew Dickson, 1832-1918.
July 30, 1906, acknowledging a copy of Cross's History of St. Andrews Church.
White, Lee A., b. 1886.
March 29, 1918
Winship, George Parker, 1871-1952.
Jan. 8, 1902-June 2, 1924
Woolley, Joseph William.
Feb. 24, 28, 1908
Yost, Fielding Harris, 1871-1946.
May 27, 1918
Ziwet, Alexander, 1853-1928.
Biographical sketch of Alexander Ziwet by Cross on Ziwet's death.